<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Joshua Lammon</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Joshua Lammon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Chart Business</title>
      <link>/blog/bar-chart-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/bar-chart-business/</guid>
      <description>In this lesson on Data Scientology we will be constructing a bar plot on the 1980 MLB Team Homerun Distribution.
First, like always, we must upload necessary libraries needed to perform the time series function. The three libraries we need are as follows:
library(Lahman) library(sqldf) library(ggplot2) Next, we must execute a query to extract the data we want to create a bar plot on. We want to see how many homeruns each MLB team totaled in 1980.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histograms 101</title>
      <link>/blog/histograms-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/histograms-101/</guid>
      <description>Let’s create a histogram that analyzes the body weight distribution of all MLB baseball players.
First, we must upload the three necessary libraries needed to perform the histogram function. These three include the Lahman, sqldf, and ggplot2 libraries.
library(Lahman) library(sqldf) library(ggplot2) Second, we must execute a query to extract the data for all MLB players’ weight.
# extracting the data query&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;SELECT weight FROM Master&amp;quot; result&amp;lt;-sqldf(query) Next, we want to write a “ggplot” function that will allow us to create the histogram and visualize the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Lessons</title>
      <link>/blog/time-series-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/time-series-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to Data Scientology. Today we will be looking at how to create a time series plot on some Babe Ruth’s HR career homerun totals.
First, like always, we must upload necessary libraries needed to perform the time series function. The three libraries we need are as follows:
library(Lahman) library(sqldf) library(ggplot2) Next, we must execute a query to extract the data we want to create a time-series plot on. We want each year Babe Ruth played in the MLB and we also want his homerun totals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatterplot Tutorial</title>
      <link>/blog/scatterplot-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/scatterplot-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to Data Scientology. Today we will be looking at how to create a scatterplot on MLB career homerun totals versus career strikeouts.
First, like always, we must upload necessary libraries needed to perform the time series function. The three libraries we need are as follows:
library(Lahman) library(sqldf) library(ggplot2) Next, we must execute a query to extract the data we want to create a scatterplot on. We want to select all players by playerID, their homerun totals and strikeout totals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>